Guide to the Jean Maddock Clark Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Jean Maddock Clark papers
1925-1986
1925-1943
SC0418
Clark, Jean Maddock
7 Linear feet
Papers largely concern her life as a Stanford student and include correspondence with her family 1930-1932; notes, papers, and exams, 1925-1943; Stanford memorabilia; alumni papers; and photographs. Also included are bedding, draperies, pillows, and stuffed animals Clark used in her dormitory room.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Jean M. Clark, 1992.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Jean M. Clark earned her a.b. in biological sciences at Stanford University in 1932 and her a.m. in education in 1944. She taught school in Phoenix, Arizona, from 1932 until her retirement in 1975. She attended summer sessions at Stanford from 1939 to 1943, earning her master's degree in education in 1944. She was active in the Stanford Alumni Association and a volunteer fund-raiser for the University.
Description of the Collection
Papers largely concern her life as a Stanford student and include correspondence with her family 1930-1932; notes, papers, and exams, 1925-1943; Stanford memorabilia; alumni papers; and photographs. Also included are bedding, draperies, pillows, and stuffed animals Clark used in her dormitory room.
Access Terms
Clark, Jean Maddock; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education.; Education--Study and teaching (Graduate); Photoprints.; Students--California.; Teachers--Training of.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence with family, 11232 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with family, November-December 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with family, January-February 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with family, March-April 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with family, May-June 193 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with family, September-October 1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with family, November-December 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with family, January-February 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with family, March-April 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with family, May-June, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Outgoing letters, 1932, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Incoming letters, 1930-1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - S .U. registration cards and transcript, master's degree candidacy application, 1930-1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Commencement 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Commencement 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford calendar, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Class of '32 fund-raising (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford fundraising (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alumni activities (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - S.U. memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Biographical (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Class Files
  - American government (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American history (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American history (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biology notes, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biology/botany notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biology notes, Phoenix Junior College (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Biology notes, Phoenix Junior College (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Biology notes, Phoenix Junior College (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Biology notes, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Comparative anatomy, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Stanford Class Files
  - Botany 142, plant physiology, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chemistry 1, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Education 164, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Education 164, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Education 182, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Education 182, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History of Education chart, 1939 (Sands & A1mack) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Education 190, growth and maturation, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Education 190, growth and maturation, 1943 (reading notes) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Education 190, growth and maturation, 1943 (exams) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Education 194, mental hygiene of school and community (syllabus and notes), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Education 194, mental hygiene of school and community, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Education 195, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Education 195, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Education 200/205, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Education 202, guidance, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Education 234, guidance in education institutions, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Education 234, guidance in education institutions, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Education 261, educational pyschology, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Education 261, educational sociology II, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Education 306, character education (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Papers from several education courses (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Principles of Education, syllabus and workbook, c. 1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notes from several education classes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reading notes, education, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reading and vocational interests tests (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - English 15, interational literature, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Themes, English classes (?), 1928 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - English literature notes (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - English literature and economics, notes (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Philosopy, background of Christianity, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Philosopy 140, religion, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Physiology 101, 1931 (notes) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Physiology 101, 1931 (notes and drawings) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Physiology 101, 1931 (lab notebook) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Physiology 101, 1931 (lab notes and exams) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Physiology 102, 1932 (notes) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Physiology 102, 1932 (lab work, drawings and exams) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sociology (Economics 2), 1931 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Spanish vocabulary notebook (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Zoology 100 (notes and drawings) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Zoology 101, classification of insects, 1931 (notes) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Zoology 102, insects and disease, 1931 (notes and exams) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Zoology 104 (chart) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Zoology 158, bionomics, 1932 (notes) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Zoology, comparative embryology, 1932 (notes and drawings) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Zoology, comparative embryology, 1932 (notes) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zoology, notes, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous class items (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Memorabilia: S.U. buttons, pins, penant, postcards, pens, etc.; and dresser jars and pillow from her dormitory room (Box 6)
  - Memorabilia: bedspread, draperies, and pillows from her dormitory room (Box 7)
  - Memorabilia: stuffed animals from her dormitory room (Box 8)
  - Memorabilia: writing blotter, pictures, and a picture frame from her dormitory room (Box 9)